Your signature technique
currently has exactly two major flaws.
Huh?
[singer singing in Japanese]
[singer singing in English]
COMPASSION X AND X STRENGTH
[narrator] Gon has finally challenged
Knuckle to a serious fight.
However, Knuckle claims
that Gon's technique has major flaws.
[Gon] Uh-oh.
I forgot to give my attack a name.
What should it be?
It's Ja… Janken.
Ja-jan Ken, huh?
Okay. I see.
So it's just like rock, paper, scissors,
but the "ja-jan" adds a little oomph,
like a "ta-da!"
Well, not really.
The first "ja" was actually a stutter.
[Killua] You are?
[Knuckle] Well, Gon,
your Jajanken has two giant weaknesses.
Those few precious seconds
you're taking before the move
is like an eternity in actual combat,
[grunts]
See, the more aura
you focus into your fist,
the less you have at your disposal,
and that's less that you'll have
to protect your body.
If someone attacks when you're vulnerable,
you're dead.
I know what the risks are.
That's why I spent
the last month training,
to make up for them!
But there's one thing he still lacks.
-[Gon groans]
-[Knuckle] Experience.
[yells]
[Knuckle] He needs to see
more real combat.
A lot more!
He's got plenty of determination,
he's faced death many times,
and he has natural talent,
I can tell what he's protecting,
and I know what he's planning to do
and stagger my blows a little…
[Gon grunting]
[Gon] I was right. Knuckle is…
Okay.
Now I think it's time
to throw a real punch.
[Gon] He's so…
Don't blame me if you die, all right?
[Gon] He's so kind.
[Knuckle] Behind you!
[Gon] He doesn't have to teach me,
but still he keeps giving me advice.
[grumbles]
[groaning]
Was that all you got?
Huh?
So act like it. Fight to kill!
Show me… rock!
[Gon] Here goes.
Jan…
[yells]
All right, now show me rock!
Jan…
[Knuckle] That little bastard,
he faked me out with his Jajanken.
You were focused
on stopping my special technique.
Even I could tell exactly how and when
you were about to strike with your right.
[Killua] He used Jajanken's weakness,
the long windup, to his advantage.
He can't help but take a swing.
It's straight down the middle,
and he's gotta hit it.
That's the trigger.
The same thing goes for aura.
Unless it's consciously held back,
aura focuses where he tenses up,
and it balloons
the moment he tries to strike.
If the Nen user is inexperienced
or loses his cool,
the aura will either stagnate
or, conversely, flow too freely.
So act like it. Fight to kill!
[Killua] Gon pointed out
Knuckle's soft side to upset him,
which made the feint successful.
This plan is more effective on someone
who knows Jajanken's strength.
As soon as Gon initiates the attack,
fear sets in.
once the opponent
figured out how it works,
that it was flawed.
But, no, he can adapt it to any situation.
Right. Now let's start over.
[Killua] In the second attempt,
Gon was too focused on the technique,
it'll be harder to distinguish
between the feints and the real thing.
So then, did Gon know
how to overcome this weakness?
No.
He must have figured it out
during the fight.
Even in the middle of intense combat,
he's making incredible progress.
and it hasn't even been 20 minutes.
I'm using more energy
because I'm moving at the same time,
[both grunt]
He's getting used to Knuckle's speed,
so surprise blows
aren't hitting him anymore.
He doesn't have much stamina left
to maintain his aura.
Unfortunately, Jajanken requires
a huge amount of aura just to activate.
Gon's used up a lot of aura
in feints alone.
He's already used his technique
three times.
They started fighting 20 minutes ago.
If he uses Jajanken again,
that means he'll only have
a minute or two left
to fight at full strength.
[Gon panting]
Wait.
What the hell is he thinking?
[Knuckle gasping]
Now show me rock!
[Knuckle] This will definitely be
Gon's final attack.
It'll all end right here.
Janken…
paper!
[both gasp]
[Knuckle] An emission attack?
You're an enhancer, no doubt about it.
Paper's an emission, so it's much weaker.
No speed, no punch.
There can't possibly be a gimmick
in such a low-level attack.
I'll deflect it, and it's over.
[shouts]
[Gon] All right. Round two.
[Knuckle] Round two?
He used a decoy to ambush me.
No good. A Jajanken combo attack!
[Gon] Rock!
[screaming]
[groaning]
He's out cold.
-[footsteps approaching]
-Huh?
Where the hell are you going now,
you fool?
[Killua] I'm heading back.
Aren't you going to fight me?
I'm ready for more.
You can fight with Gon again tomorrow.
The outcome will probably be different.
He'd better be ready to die!
but if you lose
without fighting at full strength,
I won't forgive you.
and furthermore, why are you allowing them
to criticize you for it?
Bastard.
You're pretty damn cocky when
you're not shaking in your boots, huh?
In case you forgot,
it's been a whole month,
and all you've done is stalk them.
I'll do it.
Tomorrow, I…
[Biscuit] Don't worry.
I gave him a massage,
so he'll be able to fight
in top form tomorrow.
Killua's the real issue.
I mean, I really wasn't expecting him
to go the entire month
without fighting once.
Killua!
Huh? [gasps]
Prepare yourself to fight me.
[muscles shifting]
[Gon] Whoa! What happened to your face?
I was training with Bisky.
Are you sure she wasn't torturing you?
Anyway, what about you?
Are you feeling okay?
[Gon] Yeah, I feel fantastic.
I used up all my aura,
so I expected that I would be pretty much
wiped out right now, but look!
That gorilla…
I mean, the old hag's massage
must have worked.
-[sighs] That was close.
-Huh?
Listen up. If you tell anyone
what happened yesterday,
I'll make your face three times worse.
You got it? [laughs]
She really meant it too.
[Biscuit] Well?
Are you able to see your weakness now?
[panting]
You give up far too easily,
and you're much too cautious in combat.
I'd even go so far as to say
you underestimate yourself.
Every time you face an opponent
you perceive is stronger than you,
you fight to escape, not to win.
It's a problem, but I realize
it's not one of your making.
It's the fault
of whoever taught you how to fight.
[gasps]
A habit that's as deeply ingrained
as this one is will be difficult to break,
but one thing is for sure.
For example, C on his best day
can beat D on his worst.
A, B, and C can,
under the proper circumstances,
beat D
in spite of the large power differential.
But that's them.
You, on the other hand,
assume the enemy is always at their best.
Even against enemies of equal strength,
you think, "He's tough,"
or, "It'd be dangerous if he did this."
You would run,
because you think like a loser.
You need to overcome
this bad habit right away.
And tomorrow…
if you can't defeat Shoot,
you must stay out of Gon's life.
-Let's go.
-Okay.
A love that's abnormal,
obsessive, and distorted.
It's a curse that will take
an enormous amount of effort to break.
[door creaks]
[Nen whooshing]
[Killua] As to who will emerge victorious,
I honestly don't know.
[Knuckle] So whoever loses…
[Gon] Gives up their tile to the winner.
[narrator] Gon and Knuckle,
Killua and shoot,
their long-awaited final battle begins.
[closing theme music playing]
[singer singing in Japanese]
[upbeat music playing]
[Killua] Are you saying I'm cursed, fool?
[singer singing in Japanese]